Jonathan Witcoski

Arlington, VA (570) 582-3933 jwitcoski@gmail.com

Key Qualifications

10 years experience in GIS analysis, implementation, development, execution, and location intelligence and analytics

Active Security Clearance

Software: ESRI Arc10, MS Office Suite, SPSS, ERDAS, AutoCAD, Google Earth, Arc Explorer, ArcGIS Server Programming and Markup Languages: SQL, Python, KML, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Drupal (CMS),

MySQL, Various web mapping APIs, JQuery, UI/UX, GeoServer, Leaflet, Mapbox, CartoDB

Education

Master of Science in Geography, University of Tennessee at Knoxville. (August 2007)

Concentrations in GIS and Economic Geography

Advisor: Dr. Thomas Bell

Bachelor of Arts, Penn State University (double major in Geography and Anthropology) (May 2004) Minor in Geographic Information Science from Penn State University

Technology Summary

Clearances: Active Secret Clearance, DHS Suitability Clearance, DHS Badged

Awards and Client Booz Allen Performance and Team Awards (November 2011, February 2011, December 2013, Pecognition: January 2014) Certificate of Appreciation, Geospatial Support Team, DHS (November 2010)

Languages: SQL, Python, KML, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, MySQL, Various web mapping APIs, JQuery

Software: ESRI Arc10 and ArcServer, MS Office Suite, SPSS, SAS, ERDAS, AutoCAD, Map guide, Hurrevac,

SLOSH, HAZUS, ArcGIS Server, Drupal (CMS)

Professional Appointments

C2 Solutions Group Inc./L3 Communications - Reston, VA

GIS Systems Administrator, (May 2014 to current) Responsible for the programming, scripting, installation, configuration, administration and management of the GIS tool suite. Provide administrative and technical support of ESRI-based GIS systems to ARNG-ILI and ARNG-ILE divisions

Booz Allen Hamilton – Arlington, VA

Jr. Systems Developer, (Feb 2014 to May 2014) Help provide technical solutions to a small team on a Bootstrap and Codeigniter based FEMA web development projects using HTML, CSS, MYSQL, Javascript, and Jquery in Linux environment.

Executive Briefing Team Geospatial Analyst, (2013 to May 2014) Provides geospatial mapping and analysis to the Infrastructure Protection Division of the Department of Homeland Security Executive Staff during morning briefs, exercises, steady state or special events, and response efforts to manmade or natural disasters.

- Provide geospatial support during morning briefings and quicklook products during manmade or natural disasters.
- Frequent use of data conversion, analysis, location intelligence and analytics in day to day roles

Headquarters Geospatial Analyst, (2012 to 2013) Provides geospatial mapping and analysis to the Infrastructure Protection Division of the Department of Homeland Security during exercises, steady state or special events, and response efforts to manmade or natural disasters.

- Helped lead the current project team overseeing map quality control and mentoring new hires into the team role within the government department.
- Works with and integrates a variety of data sources for map products (e.g., HSIP, USGS, US Census, FEMA, National Hydrography Dataset, US Army Corps National Levee Database, etc.)
- Supports coordination efforts between local, State, Federal (DOD, NGA, USGS) and private partners to develop implementation strategies and identify sources of spatial data

Regional Geospatial Analyst, (2009 to 2012) Provides geospatial mapping and analysis to eleven DHS Protective Security Advisers (PSAs) in the Mid-Atlantic Region (DC, DE, MD, PA, VA, WV) and in 2009-2010 11 PSAs in the Northeast Region (CT, NH, NJ, NY, MA, ME, RI, VT) during exercises, steady state or special events, and response efforts to man-made or natural disasters.

- Supports coordination efforts between local, State, Federal (DOD, NGA, USGS) and private partners to develop implementation strategies and identify sources of spatial data
- Communicates daily with the PSAs, and provides trainings and presentations to educate them about the role of GIS in enhancing their everyday work

Tyco Telecommunications - Morristown, NJ

GIS Specialist, (2007 to 2009) Developed a spatial database of underwater telecommunication cables, sonar data, and various other information of relevance to the company. Prepared various tables, maps, and graphs for use in the completion of final reports and internal spatial data queries

WDG Location Consulting- Bridgewater, NJ

GIS Specialist, (2007) Assist location consultants by providing relevant information from varied secondary sources of information. Prepare various tables, maps, and graphs from the information to be used in reports.

Philmont Scout Ranch-Cimarron, NM

GIS Specialist, (2007) Summer position operating GPS and GIS software and hardware to map various aspects of the Philmont backcountry.

Department of Geography, The University of Tennessee - Knoxville, TN

Graduate Teaching Assistant, (2004 to 2007)

- (2005-2007) Held open lab hours at the Geography Departments GIS lab to assist students with their assignments and projects. Assisted in instructing three laboratory sections for Geography 411: Computer Mapping and Geographic Information Systems.
- (2004-2005) Teaching Assistant for a course in introductory world regional geography. Responsible for supervising and grading one hundred students during their period in this cultural geography class.

University of Tennessee Archeology Research Laboratory - Knoxville, TN

GIS Technician, (2004) Performed data analysis and helped build a GIS database from several prehistoric and historic sites in association with the improvement of section of State Route 73 (U.S. 321) in Tockaleechee Cove, in Townsend, Tennessee. I also took part in an archeological survey of the Cumberland National Recreation Area on the Kentucky, Tennessee, and Virginia border.

University of Tennessee Archeology Research Laboratory - Knoxville, TN

GIS Technician, (2004) Performed data analysis and helped build a GIS database from several prehistoric and historic sites in association with the improvement of section of State Route 73 (U.S. 321) in Tockaleechee Cove, in Townsend, Tennessee. I also took part in an archeological survey of the Cumberland National Recreation Area on the Kentucky, Tennessee, and Virginia border.

National Geographic Society - Washington D.C.

Intern, (2003) Responsible for tracking specific data from grant programs; assisted in researching backgrounds and information for potential grant applicants; and prepared reports for the expert advisory panel and the National Geographic Education Foundation Board of Directors.